Obioha Vigilus Ugochukwu

Plot 288, Adulphus Wabara Street, Wuye District, FCT Abuja. Male | Nigerian | July 17. obiohaugo1@gmail.com 07034318334

PROFILE SUMMARY

A graduate of Physics & Industrial Physics (Electronics) from Nnamdi Azikiwe University Awka. Obtained a Certificate in Health Safety and Environment (HSE) 1&2 at the Project Management Professional Institute (PMPI) OSHA and DPR accredited; also have a certificate in CCTV and GPS installation and maintenance. Experienced working with Microsoft Windows OS/Office suite and Mac OSX. (MS Word, Power point, Excel). Disciplined Self-taught Programmer.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Strong Python programming language skills
- Ability to use JavaScript technology
- Able to use ProgreSQL Database
- Has Skills in the use of MySQL
- Great skills in the use of Content Management Systems (CMS)
- Strong communication and analytical skills, critical thinker.
- Good Design skills (Corel Draw and Photoshop)
- Professional Social media and SEO skills
- Fast learner, committed, passionate, techsavvy.
- Self-driven with demonstrated expertise in decision making and policy formulation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PureWeb Technologies Ltd [www.pureweb.com.ng]

2018 till date

Suite 110 FairTrade Business Complex Bambari Crescent Wuse zone 7 FCT Abuja.

HTML / CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Python and Use of CMS

- Use of Python (Django) in creating dynamic websites
- Working CMS in creating stunning web designs
- Designing of standalone Desktop and Web apps in python
- Created a mini Space Invader game with Python.
- Doing web scrapping with BeautifulSoup4 package.

Mc Dorsey Services Ltd

January 2017 - Nov 2017

33 Moloney Street, Opposite Kam Salem Police HQ, Lagos Island.

Area Sales/ Marketing Executive

- Arrange, implement and monitor marketing and sales campaigns.
- Ensure that projects are completed as scheduled within set budget.
- Resolve complex customer issues and needs.
- Participate in all strategy sessions to identify clients and prospects on sales opportunities.

Brain Factor Merchants Ltd

April 2016 - Dec 2016

193, KiriKiri Road, Olodi Apapa Lagos, Nigeria.

Sales Executive

- Advertising / marketing of various goods in stock.
- Taking records of daily sales made.
- Keeping the company sales records accurate and up to date.
- Negotiating with customers for favorable prices, agreement between the customer and the company

Remedial College Emure Ekiti State Nigeria

March 2015 - April 2016

Physics Teacher (NYSC – Primary Assignment)

- Teaching and preparing students of final year class in physics for their WAEC and UTME exams.
- Given the student future talk and seminar on future goals and how to achieve them.
- Setting mock exams to test the assimilation of the subject content and syllabus to ascertain their level of preparedness for the above said examinations.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Participated in the Recode Nigeria Hackaton, organized by the African Fintech Foundry in Lagos and sponsored by IBM, Microsoft, Unilever, Access Bank and Coca-Cola.
- Self taught programmer who has grown tremendously; created Desktop apps, web apps and stunning websites
- Increased sales by 15% within the first 3 months of engagement.
- Proffered solutions to age time difficulty in penetrating a key area as a result, increased general growth of turnover.
- Use of social media in creating awareness of the products and services and also achieving massive patronage.

EDUCATION

| Self-Taught Programmer Via Books, Online Materials and Codecademy, Udemy | till date |
|--|-------------|
| Nnamdi Azikiwe University Awka BSc – Physics and Industrial Physics | 2010 – 2014 |
| Awodi-Ora Senior Secondary School Lagos Senior School Certificate (SSCE) | 2000 – 2006 |
| Ajeromi Ifelodun Primary School First School Leaving Certificate | 1995 –2000 |

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

Project Management Professional Institute (PMPI)

Health Safety and Environment (HSE 1&2)

January, 2016

Bugotake Technology

CCTV, GPS, OBD, PABX, Radio frequency (installation and maintenance)

March, 2016

INTEREST AND ACTIVITIES

Programming, reading wide, researching on investment options and networking.

REFERENCES

Mr Godwin Emmanuel MOD Eduction Nigeria Ltd 7 Hughes Avenue, Alagomeji, Yaba Lagos Nigeria 08030680079

Mrs Nkechi Asuzu Advanced Int'l Merchants Ltd Lagos Nigeria 08033970403